A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Program Division, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of James H. Lapple FA683
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Program Division, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of James H. Lapple
1977-1997 (Bulk: 1985-1991)
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA683
4.8 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Field Office Files, I
  - Field Office Visits and Accounting Software Installation, 1985-1990; I.1
    - Kenya Trip (August 1986), Aug 1986 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Trip (December 1986), Dec 1986 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Trip (December 1986) -- Thailand, Dec 1986 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Trip (December 1986) -- Manila, Dec 1986 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Trip (December 1986) -- Trip Report, Jan 21, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Trip (December 1986) -- Thank You Notes, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Mexico Trip (February 1987) -- Mexico City Field Office Accounting, Administrative Policies, New Personnel, Budget Information, etc., 1985-1987 (Box 1)
    - Mexico Trip (February 1987) -- Preliminary Agenda (Box 1)
    - Cairo Implementation (June 1987) -- Agenda, Jun 1987 (Box 1)
    - Cairo Implementation (June 1987) -- Ariela's Report (floppy disk), Jun 1987 (Box 1)
    - Cairo Implementation (June 1987) -- Trip Report, Jul 13, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Cairo Implementation (June 1987) -- Miscellaneous Memoranda (Box 1)
    - Brazil Implementation (August 1987) -- Pre-Implementation Memo and Subject Category Codes (Box 1)
    - Brazil Implementation (August 1987) -- Agenda (Box 1)
    - West Africa Trip (September 1987) -- Lagos (Box 1)
    - West Africa Trip (September 1987) -- Senegal Follow-Up Request, Mar 22, 1988 (Box 1)
    - West Africa Trip (September 1987) -- Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Mexico Implementation (February 1988) -- Pre-Implementation Memo, Jan 12, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Mexico Implementation (February 1988) -- Agenda, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Mexico Implementation (February 1988) -- Trip Report, Mar 22, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Jakarta Pre-Implementation (March 1988) (Box 1)
    - China Field Visit (May 1988) (Box 1)
    - China Field Visit (May 1988) -- Agenda (on floppy disks) (Box 1)
    - Kenya Implementation (June 1988) -- Pre-Implementation Memo, Apr 25, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Kenya Implementation (June 1988) -- Implementation Report, Jun 24, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Kenya Implementation (June 1988) -- Kenya Programming Changes Memo, Apr 14, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Kenya Implementation (June 1988) -- Miscellaneous Memoranda and Materials (incl. floppy disks) (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Installation (August 1988) -- Pre-Implementation Memo -- Bangkok, Jun 23, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Installation (August 1988) -- Pre-Implementation Memo -- Jakarta, Jun 23, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Installation (August 1988) -- Pre-Implementation Memo -- Manila, Jun 23, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Installation (August 1988) -- Pre-Implementation Trip Report/Sample Report Index, Mar 23, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Installation (August 1988) -- Bangkok/Manila Changes (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Installation (August 1988) -- Field Office Budget Submissions Fiscal Year 1989 (Box 1)
    - Southeast Asia Installation (August 1988) -- Accounting Software Implementation Memos (Box 1)
    - Bangladesh/India Visit (January 1989) -- Agenda and Handwritten Notes (Box 1)
    - Bangladesh/India Visit (January 1989) -- Bangladesh Visit, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - Bangladesh/India Visit (January 1989) -- India Visit, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
    - Kenya Modification Visit (March 1989) -- Agenda (Box 2)
    - Kenya Modification Visit (March 1989) -- Trip Report and Trip-Related Memoranda and Notes, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Senegal Financial Accounting Software Installation (May 1989) (incl. disks) (Box 2)
    - Peru Installation (October 1989) -- [incl. PHOTO and FLOPPY DISKS] (Box 2)
    - China Installation (November 1989) [incl. FLOPPY DISKS] (Box 2)
    - Kenya/Harare Installation Visit (June-July 1990), 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - India/Egypt Trip (March-April 1990), 1988-1990 (Box 2)
    - Indonesia Version -- Financial Accounting Software (Box 2)
  - Field Office Administration, Program Reviews, Conferences, Grants Systems, 1977-1997; I.2
    - Bangkok Field Office Administration Manual and Materials, 1977-1995 (Box 2)
    - Bangladesh Field Office Administration Manual and Materials, 1981-1997 (Box 2)
    - Developing Countries Program Fiscal Year 1987 Administration and Accounting Meeting -- Discussion Materials Prepared by Office of the Secretary, Oct 21, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Accounting Conference (DCP FY Admin and Accounting Meeting), Oct 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Accounting Conference -- Invitation and Agenda, Oct 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Accounting Conference -- Detailed Agenda, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Accounting Conference -- Individual Grants, Oct 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Accounting Conference -- Memos to Representatives, Nov 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Accounting Conference -- OTJ Logistical Review, [1986] (Box 2)
    - Field Office Accounting Conference -- Investment, Role of, Oct 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- Accounting Practices and Procedures and Foreign Currency Memo, Mar 10, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- Organizational Charts for Field Offices, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- Names and Addresses (of Representatives), Jan 1987 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- Overseas Grant Payment Memo, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- 1987 Program Review (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- 1988 Budget Instructions, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- Program Review Fiscal Year 1989, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- MIS Support for Field Offices Memo, Jul 20, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Field Office Administration -- Budget Instructions, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Brazil and India Grants Systems, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Cairo Grants System, 1990 (Box 3)
    - China Grants System, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Indonesia Grants System, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Kenya Grants System, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Mexico Grants System, 1987-1990 (Box 3)
    - Peru Grants System, 1990 (Box 3)
- Budget Files and Program Reviews, 1988-1991; II
  - Financial Statements and Quarterly Projections, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Monthly Financial Statements, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Mexico FAP Visit/Review (August 1989), Aug 1989 (Box 3)
  - January 1990 Budget Review (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Reports -- Regional Offices Fiscal Year 1990, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Roster and Staff Count (March 1990), Mar 1990 (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- OVP and USIAP and DCP Grants Administration (110/111/216), 1989 (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- Urban Poverty (120), [1989-1990] (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- Human Rights and Governance (130), 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- International Affairs Program (140) (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- Education and Culture (150), 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- Rural Poverty and Resources (170) (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- PRI (610), 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- Asia (230), 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- Africa and the Middle East (240), 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Cost Center Budget Report FY 1990 -- Latin America and the Caribbean (250) (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation Program Division -- March 1990 Budget Review, Mar 1990 (Box 3)
  - Budget Fiscal Year 1991 -- 110/205, 1990 (Box 4)
  - USIAP Program Review, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Quarterly Budget Project Fiscal Year 1991, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
- Memoranda and Miscellaneous Reports, 1987-1990; III
  - Memoranda, 1987-1990 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Reports by Lapple Re: Brand Quality, Debt Conversion, etc. (for class?), 1988 (Box 4)